<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class name="FmodServer" inherits="Object" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/godotengine/godot/master/doc/class.xsd">
	<brief_description>
		Global singleton that manages the FMOD audio system lifecycle.
	</brief_description>
	<description>
		FmodServer is a global singleton that manages the FMOD Core API audio system within Godot. It initializes and maintains the main FMOD System instance, registers performance monitors for tracking CPU and file usage, manages the audio bus layout, and connects to Godot's SceneTree for per-frame updates.
		The server automatically initializes during GDExtension loading and handles all FMOD lifecycle management. It creates performance monitors that can be viewed in Godot's Debugger > Monitor tab to track FMOD's resource usage.
		[b]Performance Monitors:[/b]
		The following custom monitors are registered with Godot's Performance system:
		- [code]FmodCPUUsage/DSP[/code]: DSP processing CPU usage percentage
		- [code]FmodCPUUsage/Stream[/code]: Stream decoding CPU usage percentage
		- [code]FmodCPUUsage/Geometry[/code]: 3D geometry processing CPU usage percentage
		- [code]FmodCPUUsage/Update[/code]: System update CPU usage percentage
		- [code]FmodCPUUsage/Convolution1[/code]: Convolution reverb 1 CPU usage percentage
		- [code]FmodCPUUsage/Convolution2[/code]: Convolution reverb 2 CPU usage percentage
		- [code]FmodFileUsage/SampleBytesRead[/code]: Sample bytes read from disk
		- [code]FmodFileUsage/StreamBytesRead[/code]: Stream bytes read from disk
		- [code]FmodFileUsage/OtherBytesRead[/code]: Other bytes read from disk
		[b]Note:[/b] This class is a singleton. Use the static methods directly to access FMOD systems and shared resources.
	</description>
	<tutorials>
	</tutorials>
	<methods>
		<method name="get_audio_bus_layout" qualifiers="static">
			<return type="FmodAudioBusLayout" />
			<description>
				Returns the audio bus layout used for managing audio buses and their routing. The bus layout synchronizes with Godot's AudioServer bus layout and provides FMOD-specific bus functionality including DSP effects.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_main_system" qualifiers="static">
			<return type="FmodSystem" />
			<description>
				Returns the main FMOD System instance. This is the primary interface for creating sounds, channels, DSP effects, and other FMOD objects. The system is automatically initialized during server startup with settings from ProjectSettings.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_master_channel_group" qualifiers="static">
			<return type="FmodChannelGroup" />
			<description>
				Returns the master channel group that all sounds route through by default. This is the root of the channel group hierarchy and can be used to control global volume, pitch, and effects for all playing sounds.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methods>
</class>
